A useful optimization claim needs more than one
favorable number.
ArmQuantLab keeps model size, numerical parity,
protocol, and every measured batch together, including
the two cases where INT8 is slower.
The decision has three parts.
Is the model smaller?
Are outputs still numerically aligned?
And for which batch shapes is latency actually better?
Each answer is tied to the same frozen model hashes
and benchmark report.
The frozen run uses native Arm64, ONNX Runtime's CPU
provider, and one CPU thread.
Each batch gets ten warm-ups, forty measured samples,
and two hundred invocations per sample.
The video does not rerun or replace those metrics.
The workflow creates a deterministic ONNX graph, runs
shape and graph preprocessing, then applies dynamic
per-channel INT8 weight quantization.
FP32 and INT8 receive the same deterministic inputs
before the evidence is frozen.
The preprocessed FP32 model is one million four
hundred forty-six thousand nine hundred eighty-nine
bytes.
INT8 is three hundred seventy-two thousand nine
hundred five bytes, a measured reduction of
seventy-four point two two nine percent.
Compression is not useful if the output diverges.
Across batches one, eight, and thirty-two, cosine
similarity remains above zero point nine nine nine
eight nine.
The report also keeps maximum and mean absolute error.
Batch eight improves p50 latency by one point two
eight two times.
Batch one slows to zero point seven nine five times,
and batch thirty-two slows to zero point six four five
times.
ArmQuantLab keeps all three rows visible.
The speedup profile is non-monotonic.
INT8 wins only at batch eight in this fixture.
That makes the next engineering question concrete:
match optimization to the real batch profile instead
of treating INT8 as automatically faster.
A separate command can process a compatible model the
operator is authorized to use.
It rejects symlinks, external tensor files, oversized
models, unresolved shapes, and unsupported ops, while
keeping the model and derivatives local.
The public fixture collects no hostname, username,
account data, credential, source path, or input value.
It proves reproducible runtime optimization and
numerical parity, not production task accuracy or
universal performance.
The release verifier confirms native Arm64, three
measured batches, a smaller INT8 model, output parity,
model hashes, and a zero-finding public-text privacy
scan.
Six tests also cover deterministic generation and the
compatible-model gates.
ArmQuantLab makes the trade-off reviewable.
The model is substantially smaller, output parity
remains high, one batch is faster, and two are slower.
That honest profile is more useful than a universal
optimization claim.